Leon An-Sheng MAK Mobile: +65 8268 5621

Email: <u>leon.mak@u.nus.edu</u>

Skype: leonmakansheng@gmail.com

Github: github.com/leonmak

Online Portfolio: <u>leonmak.me/projects</u> Online Resume: <u>leonmak.me/resume</u>



Personal Statement

1. Internship Objectives

Firstly, to gain practical insight, not just in applying my technical skills in a realistic setting, but also related areas like product design and system architecture, that are not so much covered in university but relevant in creating modern products and services.

Also, I want to learn more about the startup scene and the people in Silicon Valley, in particular the opportunities and growth areas that are available and how entrepreneurs capitalize on them. Finally, I want to understand the culture and people in the industry, as well as to understand how companies improve their product, technology and design strategies and the decisions they make.

2. About Me

I am a Year 2 Computer Science Major, pursuing focus areas in Artificial Intelligence and Software Engineering. I am a full stack web developer who started out in front end web development, and I also do mobile app development on IOS. I also like tinkering with new technologies in my spare time.

3. Strengths & Weaknesses

I have a willingness to explore different things. For example, I like starting side projects to see what result I can achieve. I believe this is a strength as it has helped to broaden my perspective and make me think differently.

I like to dabble in many things and sometimes I feel like I lack depth in completing or extending some of my existing projects. I recognize that having a deep focus even when there are no immediately gratifying results can yield important results, and I continue to strive to find a balance between exploiting what I know and exploring new ideas.

4. Unique Skill Sets

I'm like designing and developing products especially web products, and delight in making a design become reality.

5. How Can I Contribute

I have experience designing and developing products for a variety of users, the most immediate group being fellow students such as myself, some for variety of users, and also developers on open source projects.

Education

Aug 2015 - Present

National University of Singapore (NUS)

Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science
(Course details in Appendix A)

Singapore

Jan 2010 - Dec 2012 Raffles Institution (Junior College)

Singapore

Singapore-Cambridge General Certificate of Education Advanced Level
Subjects: Chemistry(A), Mathematics(A), Economics(A), Physics (B)

Work Experience

Jan 2015 – May 2015 Action X Private Limited

Singapore

Singapore

Front End Web Developer & Graphic Design

- Developed website for race signups in Asia and localized for China
- · Collaborated with marketing team on design of race publications

Scholastic Achievements/Extracurricular Activities

Feb 2017 **NUS IDEa\$ Challenge – Innovate, Design, Engineer, and Sell** Singapore 2nd Prize

2^{rrs} Prize

Project: http://1our.today - NUS Student Jobs Platform

Aug 2015 - Dec 2016 School Contributions

• Marketing Director for NUS Enactus (Social Entrepreneurship Society)

Project Director for Coding for Social Good (Teaching basic computer)

programming to underprivileged children)

Skill Sets & Proficiency

Web HTML, CSS **Proficient Proficient** Javascript, ES6 Basic

PHP

ReactJS, AngularJS Intermediate MeteorJS Intermediate

Mobile Swift 3, IOS 10 Intermediate

Design Adobe Photoshop Proficient Adobe Illustrator Intermediate **Proficient**

Sketch

Database SQL - MySQL, PostgreSQL DBMS Intermediate

NoSQL - MongoDB

Programming languages Proficient Java

Proficient Swift 3 Javascript **Proficient** Python Intermediate C Basic C++ **Basic** C# **Basic**

Intermediate

Basic

DevOps Docker Basic

Kubernetes

Markup XML, JSON, BSON Basic

Non-technical Skills Project Management Basic

Writing/Publications Basic

Language Proficiency

Spoken English - fluent; Mandarin - average Written English - competent; Chinese - average

Additional Information

http://leonmak.me/projects View my projects at:

Degree: Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science

Cumulative Average Point: 4.31 / 5.00

Year	Level	Course Description	Grades
Aug – Nov 2015	Year 1/Semester 1	Programming Methodology	S
		Discrete Structures	B+
		Quantitative Reasoning	S
		Linear Algebra I	B+
		Calculus For Computing	B+
Jan – May 2016	Year 1/Semester 2	Data Structures and Algorithms	А
		Computer Organisation	B+
		Computing And Society	Α
		Reason And Persuasion	B+
		Probability And Statistics	Α
Aug – Nov 2016	Year 2/Semester 1	Independent Work	CS
		Software Product Engineering For Digital Markets	Α
		Data Structures And Algorithms II	B+
		Introduction To Computer Networks	В
		Einstein's Universe & Quantum Weirdness	S
		General Biology	B+
Jan – May 2017	Year 2/Semester 2	Effective Communication for Computing Professionals	In Progress
		Software Engineering on Modern Application Platforms	In Progress
		Software Engineering	In Progress
		Urban Planning in Singapore	In Progress
		Introduction to Artificial Intelligence	In Progress

NUS Grading Scale:

 $A+ \& \ A \ (5.0); \ A- \ (4.5); \ B+ \ (4.0); \ B \ (3.5); \ B- \ (3.0); \ C+ \ (2.5); \ C \ (2.0); \ D+ \ (1.5); \ D \ (1.0); \ F \ (0)$

S = Satisfactory; U = Unsatisfactory

CS = Completed Satisfactorily; CU = Completed Unsatisfactorily

EXE = Exempted; IC = Incomplete; IP = In Progress; W = Withdrawn